Exercise 6-2, sounds comparing L with T, D, and N. Repeat after me, first down and
then across. One, at the beginning of a word. La, lo, li, na, no, ni, ta, to, ti,
da, do, di, la, na, ta, da, lo, no, to, do, li, ni, ti, di. Two, in the middle of a
word, belly, collar, Alley, Benny, Connor, Annie, Betty, Cotter, at ease, Belly,
Benny, Betty, Collar, Connor, cotter alley, Annie, at ease three at the end of a word
a hole hold hone hoed call called, con, cod, be, fill, full, fool, fail, fell,
feel, fuel, furl. Look at the group 3B. This exercise has three functions. 1.
Practice final L's. 2. Review vowel sounds. 3. Review the same words with the
staircase. Note. Notice that each word has a tiny schwa after the L. This is to
encourage your tongue to be in the right position to give your words a finished
sound. Exaggerate the final L and its otherwise inaudible schwa. Repeat the last
group of words. Fill, full, fool, fail, fell, feel, fuel, furl. Once you're
comfortable with your tongue in this position, let it just languish there while
you continue vocalizing, which is what a native speaker does. Repeat again. fill,
full, fool, fail, feel, fuel, furl